BRYAN BURCIAGA

Software Engineer

(630) 362-9755 | Chicago, IL | alejandroburciaga7@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

SUMMARY

Software engineer with over 3 years of experience in business operations and business management and production. I am an Engineer with a background in business development. I work to tackle business problems by actions. I bring my passion for help into each project. My background in business and my experience with management enables me to approach each project with experience in the business field.

SKILLS

Javascript, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, MongoDB and React.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Mexico Covid Tracker| Lead Developer| Github | Deploy app

- Built a front end app called "Mexico Covid Tracker" with a SVG map of Mexico based on the daily information of a Mexican government API.
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX.

InvMag| Lead Developer| Github | Deploy app

- Designed a back-end web application called "InvMagt" which allows users to have a control of sales, a balance and create estimations immediately with your logo.
- Technologies used: HTML, Css, JavaScript, Node JS, bootstrap, express, MongoDB, heroku.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Química Durango | Business Development | Durango, Mexico. Feb 2019- May 2022

- Co-founder of "Química Durango" and part of the design and planning development of manufacturing and sales of Chemical and cleaning products.
- A 12-person team, which included the production team, management team, finances team and improvement team, where my main task was the organization of whole areas.
- Successfully achieved promotion of major products across 256 large supply chain stores throughout the local area while increasing revenue by 40,000 dlls monthly.

Supply leader, Production Supervisor | Durango, Mexico. June 2019-May 2020

 Lead a 60-person team, fiting operators in key positions to achieve the daily production goals. Achieving the daily goals and avoiding the continuous stop lines and hence the manufacture of harnesses.

Internship, Production Supervisor | Durango, Mexico. June 2018-December 2018.

- Implement records for production associates to register the daily production of each one in a 6-person team over 24 weeks with a successful result of a stable production.
- Oversaw and monitor the production records to make informed decisions on how to improve leading the machine and press operators with the production sequence to the prior orders going through the less prior to improve the daily production by 20% avoiding stopping the manufacturing lines. Resulting in 30,000 dlls in 24 weeks.

EDUCATION

General Assembly (Remote)

Software Engineering Immersive | August 2022 - November 2022

Durango Tech (Durango, Mexico)

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering, Focus in Quality | August 2013 - May 2018